[{"id": "5fea8339ff048f679a45ac26", "question": "What is the fastest sense?", "answer": "Hearing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b879", "question": "In which city does the Tour de France end?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23d", "question": "What does an Apiarist do?", "answer": "Keeps bees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339343", "question": "Who was the cook on the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Hop Sing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe2583f658e585fda9cfa3e", "question": "Black Forest cake originates from which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c861", "question": "What takes exactly eight minutes and twenty seconds to reach the earth?", "answer": "Sunlight", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b32341abf195a31e15d73a2", "question": "What desert covers most of southern Mongolia?", "answer": "The Gobi desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f5", "question": "Ronald Reagan made headlines in 1980 for claiming that 80 percent of air pollution comes from what?", "answer": "Trees", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52f571bf59ab7d2e38114", "question": "What ingredient turns a martini into a dirty martini?", "answer": "Olive juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb601b5dad637d903c8829", "question": "Which city in the U.S. is home to the National Mustard Museum?", "answer": "Middleton, Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affd", "question": "What space exploration organization was founded in 1958?", "answer": "NASA", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e99", "question": "What Greek goddess is depicted in the famous Winged Victory of Samothrace?", "answer": "Nike", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049cfccf93664eb10486ab", "question": "What is the more common name for the 1987 computer virus that was set to go off on Friday the 13th of every year?", "answer": "Jerusalem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65e461f3c0ead6880d628", "question": "What biblical figure had a slave named Onesimus?", "answer": "Philemon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8fbe501dd7bf43be5e856", "question": "Who first said, \"When you reach the end of your rope, tie a knot in it and hang on\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a94bc61d1b4d384d5d671", "question": "Who is Dana Elaine Owens more commonly known as?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff146e2b0ee8c595b6d39c1", "question": "What is the oldest operating Broadway theater?", "answer": "The Lyceum Theater", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b2", "question": "The Apgar score is used to measure the color and condition of what?", "answer": "Newborns", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b654", "question": "The hymn for what branch of the US military begins with the line: \"From the halls of Montezuma\"?", "answer": "Marine Corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab73", "question": "Dhaka is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d4", "question": "What TV character's first spoken words were \"Goodbye kids\"?", "answer": "Clarabell the Clown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac63", "question": "Which US naval base did Japan attack in 1941 to declare war on the Allies?", "answer": "Pearl Harbor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a63c", "question": "What is the westernmost state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b28a", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Bucephalus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3589855db0d66a186cb54c", "question": "The Republic of Benin shares a border with which other African country to the east?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395af", "question": "Carolyn Jones was best known for her role as what 1960s sitcom character?", "answer": "Morticia Addams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339153", "question": "What do ghouls typically feast on?", "answer": "Human flesh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594fb9a8210241017090b57e", "question": "What year did the interval act \"Riverdance\" debut at the Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4f", "question": "What fish is known as poor mans lobster?", "answer": "Monk Fish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56f", "question": "Which US state has shoreline along the Gulf of Mexico and the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51342ff04d658268c92d7", "question": "What was the goal of the Marshall Plan?", "answer": "Rebuild war-devastated regions, remove trade barriers, modernize industry, and prevent the spread of communism.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da1", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Hagen?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b04", "question": "What 2004 movie remake found Denzel Washington playing a role originated by Frank Sinatra in 1962?", "answer": "The Manchurian Candidate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb0", "question": "What modern-day conglomerate built Zero fighter planes used to bomb Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "Mitsubishi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339665", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Springfield Elementary's music teacher?", "answer": "Mr. Largo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a53", "question": "In the Golden Earring song \"Radar Love\", what country artist do they hear playing on the radio?", "answer": "Brenda Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b2", "question": "In what city would you find Champ de Mars?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c559", "question": "What color eggs do peacocks lay?", "answer": "They don't lay eggs - peacocks are male peafowl. Peahens are female and lay eggs.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ecfefe83fe1f2a824c06", "question": "How many times are Jews supposed to wash their hands at the Seder table?", "answer": "Two times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b0e8df964118b2bb3809c7", "question": "The custom of sending cards, flowers, chocolates and gifts on Valentine's Day originated in which country?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392aa", "question": "Which famous actress is Liza Minnelli's mother?", "answer": "Judy Garland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae1", "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f8", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf R32 model?", "answer": "2002", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eab", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Jughaid and Tater?", "answer": "Barney Google and Snuffy Smith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ec4a06d333868d34d763", "question": "What was the term for the official policy of racial segregation in South Africa until 1994?", "answer": "Apartheid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c9", "question": "What folk singer was born Robert Zimmerman?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f0ecf842fa4c4ba96b7", "question": "What did William H. Seward buy from Russia in 1867?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afe", "question": "What 1995 Kevin Costner film was the most expensive movie ever made, until \"Titanic\" came along in 1997?", "answer": "Waterworld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b372061c3f17ccc40c8e21", "question": "The detective novel \"The Body in the library\" was written by which novelist?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ae", "question": "Who signed off his radio show by saying \"Keep your feet on the ground and keep reaching for the stars\"?", "answer": "Casey Kasem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b3ba06d333868d34d6dc", "question": "In what year did the Korean War end?", "answer": "Although hostilities ended in 1953, there was never a formal peace treaty as of 2020", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee3", "question": "In which city was Leonardo da Vinci born?", "answer": "Vinci", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb9ae7e83c707845b213e", "question": "What kind of milk is used in chevre cheese?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6018bd8bd96d05b23b28165c", "question": "Atropos, Lachesis, and Clotho are the Three what of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Fates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa420fc73aa70ea0b70b13", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9be", "question": "Arlanda airport serves which European city?", "answer": "Stockholm", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a98e361d1b4d384d5d693", "question": "Which major lake is near the Ponderosa Ranch in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Lake Tahoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c7e5877e98cb977789d8", "question": "Which Middle Eastern country's highest elevation point is Haji Ibrahim?", "answer": "Iraq", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef8", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Isabel Archer?", "answer": "The Portrait of a Lady", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42e", "question": "Which ocean is between South America and Africa?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0c", "question": "In which US state is the Catalina Island located?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35d", "question": "Who was the first American scientist to win a Nobel prize?", "answer": "Albert Michelson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cf8e877e98cb97778a50", "question": "Until 1820, Maine was part of which US state?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c289", "question": "What is xenophobia?", "answer": "Fear of strangers or foreigners", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b0", "question": "What 1968 hit was the first to include the phrase \"heavy metal\" in its lyrics?", "answer": "Born to be Wild", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52c", "question": "The mouth of the Mississippi River is located in which state?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b571b6667df192a942e3368", "question": "What is the capital of Nicaragua?", "answer": "Managua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b8", "question": "What TV sitcom opens with the theme \"Making our Dreams Come True\"?", "answer": "Laverne and Shirley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b85d", "question": "If you had pogonophobia what would you be afraid of?", "answer": "Beards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338889", "question": "Who turned all he touched to gold?", "answer": "King Midas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f94", "question": "Who played the Keymaster in the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Rick Moranis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94d", "question": "What line on a map connects places of equal rainfall?", "answer": "Isohyet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339656", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Marge develops a serious case of what when she gets behind the wheel of her new Canyonero?", "answer": "Road rage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c6e40775fa611bce67d4", "question": "A legislature that has legislators in two separate assemblies, chambers, or houses is called what?", "answer": "Bicameral", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c99e877e98cb977789f8", "question": "On the first of November, Spain celebrates \"Todos los Santos\" which translates to what in English?", "answer": "All Saints Day", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9005501dd7bf43be5e866", "question": "How many US gallons is in a barrel of oil?", "answer": "42", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bac", "question": "What band's first Top 10 hit in the US was 1984's \"Legs\"?", "answer": "ZZ Top", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb342be368446ca7bd684a", "question": "What year was the instant coffee, Nescafe, released onto the market?", "answer": "1938", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a478", "question": "Lanzarote is part of which island group?", "answer": "The Canaries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961a", "question": "The \"Sacred Order of the Stonecutters\" was a fictional club in which TV show?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c6", "question": "What did Little Jack Horner pull out of his Christmas pie?", "answer": "A plum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390dc", "question": "Who was the author of the novel \"The Midwich Cuckoos\"?", "answer": "John Wyndham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2c", "question": "Who wrote \"Le Morte Darthur\" while in prison?", "answer": "Thomas Malory", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c724", "question": "In North America, moss typically grows heavier on the side of trees facing which direction?", "answer": "North", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecdd03ec223966ae8f88fc", "question": "Who was shown as an amputee with the use of special effects in \"Forrest Gump\"?", "answer": "Lt. Dan Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16754f7c52aae91cc07b8", "question": "Bissau is the capital of which West African country?", "answer": "Guinea-Bissau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c521", "question": "What method of underwater detection is short of \"sound navigation and ranging\"?", "answer": "Sonar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba0", "question": "Saint Petersburg is located on which river?", "answer": "Neva River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf2", "question": "When did the Hindenburg airship disaster occur?", "answer": "1937", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339444", "question": "Who played Edward in the movie \"Edward Scissorhands\"?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728cf36bcd28c11938328e", "question": "What is Steganography?", "answer": "The practice of concealing a message within another message", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008aafcf842fa4c4ba9692", "question": "Who released the 1979 song \"Rock 'n' Roll High School\"?", "answer": "The Ramones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fb", "question": "Where is the opening scene of the movie \"Love Actually\" shot?", "answer": "An airport", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a83", "question": "Which original \"Star Trek\" character was played by James Doohan?", "answer": "Scotty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca97", "question": "What animal may be Stag, Rhinoceros or Dung?", "answer": "Beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b49", "question": "Who played Al Borland on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Richard Karn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339485", "question": "Who stars as Walter Fielding Jr. in the 1986 movie \"The Money Pit\"?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fb", "question": "Who had a 1982 No.1 hit with \"Happy Talk\"?", "answer": "Captain Sensible", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb18", "question": "According to business studies, what is the most productive day of the work week?", "answer": "Tuesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c5f20775fa611bce67ce", "question": "What is currently the tallest building in the U.S.?", "answer": "One World Trade Center, NYC -- The skyscraper houses a museum and memorial to those lost in the September 11 terror attacks.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc0", "question": "Whose profile is displayed on the Purple Heart medal?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cea", "question": "Who wrote \"The Scarlett Letter\"?", "answer": "Nathaniel Hawthorne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b3", "question": "What was Tom Cruise\u2019s character\u2019s name in the \"Mission Impossible\" movie series?", "answer": "Ethan Hunt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca21", "question": "What are Common Darter and Southern Hawker types of?", "answer": "Dragonflies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b989", "question": "What is a \u2018half hunter\u2019?", "answer": "A pocket watch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51bc9ff04d658268c9310", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25146b63e5727cf5a4838", "question": "What place does Argentina take on the list of the World\u2019s largest countries by land area?", "answer": "Eighth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339479", "question": "Who won an Oscar for Best Actor in 1993 and again in 1994?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccf7aec223966ae8f88b5", "question": "What 2001 film was originally supposed to feature Bruce Willis, Mark Wahlberg, Danny Glover, Luke Wilson, and Owen Wilson?", "answer": "\"Ocean's Eleven\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87c", "question": "Sinologists study what?", "answer": "China and Chinese topics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c90cfc152800b05cac20f0b", "question": "What is the only African nation with Spanish as the official language?", "answer": "Equatorial Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb01b65ff7d326b622a60", "question": "In which continent would you find the Atlas Mountains?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6002424c4be4723ccac22183", "question": "In Chaucer\u2019s \"The Canterbury Tales\", the pilgrims are travelling to visit the shrine of which saint?", "answer": "Saint Thomas Becket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff6685052a821ff76ae8b03", "question": "Around what sea did Jesus call His first apostles?", "answer": "Christ first saw Peter and Andrew close to the Sea of Galilee. He beseeched them to follow Him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51ce2ff04d658268c931d", "question": "Who invented the rubber band?", "answer": "In 1845, Stephen Perry, of the rubber manufacturing company Messers Perry and Co., invented the rubber band.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7c1382b316f4693fb679c", "question": "May Day is not considered a public holiday in England unless it falls on which day of the week?", "answer": "Monday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede45f6ce05a3942286ddd", "question": "Who penned the classic songs \"Bad Moon Rising\", \"Who'll Stop The Rain\", and \"Lodi\"?", "answer": "John Fogarty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea77dfff048f679a45abd0", "question": "What breed of domestic cat is known for swimming?", "answer": "Turkish Van", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897d", "question": "What was Long John Silver's parrot Captain Flint favorite phrase?", "answer": "Pieces of eight", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33c", "question": "What is the name of Agrippa's husband, who she poisoned?", "answer": "Claudius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f700ea9e54d890926f6d4", "question": "South America\u2019s Atacama Desert holds what distinction?", "answer": "Driest non-polar desert -- Although it is home to about one million people, it records less than 1 mm of rain every year.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b098", "question": "What 20th \u00adcentury conflict was dubbed the \"forgotten war\"?", "answer": "The Korean War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0af9fe662d71a53650fc1", "question": "Who is the pre-Civil War author of a short story about a beating heart beneath the floorboards?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67b", "question": "What is the main source of food for the badger?", "answer": "Earthworms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37b", "question": "What is the capital of South Korea?", "answer": "Seoul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f41efa5fdd6dd25324dd", "question": "In the field of psychiatry what term described self-love?", "answer": "Narcissism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc1", "question": "What is Jon\u2019s last name in the \"Garfield\" comics?", "answer": "Arbuckle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5eb738c05e259d786908732f", "question": "Who was the first Roman Emperor?", "answer": "Augustus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a758", "question": "The island of Martha's Vineyard is located in what body of water?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3f", "question": "What is the capital of China?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133addf", "question": "What English dynasty collapsed into the Wars of the Roses?", "answer": "The Plantagenets", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e1f1fe83fe1f2a824b9a", "question": "After changing sides during World War II, what was Italy's primary objective?", "answer": "It distracted Germany from accomplishing its main objectives", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e0", "question": "Who played Mr. Brown in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b624", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is represented by a bull?", "answer": "Taurus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59decf45ea2747c8aff16d1c", "question": "How many players are there in a men's field lacrosse team?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb083c6cf631c2414a13b48", "question": "What is meteorology the study of?", "answer": "Weather Forecasting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab1b2674fda37788a9a1dba", "question": "Ouagadougou is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Burkina Faso", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6b7a3fb6c85e9e634ff4c", "question": "Which comet is visible every 74 to 79 years?", "answer": "Halley's comet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84a", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find hepatocytes?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c4", "question": "If you suffer from epistaxis what is wrong?", "answer": "Your nose is bleeding", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b699091e762b54eb9be9411", "question": "How is the number 20 written with Roman numerals?", "answer": "XX", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f164952f9b80650dbe7f92a", "question": "What is Harry Potter's middle name?", "answer": "James", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b214", "question": "Who was assassinated by Nathuram Godse?", "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b9", "question": "The city of Muskogee is located in which US state?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde4c76c6c6b019850c9a7c", "question": "What ancient people based their law on the Code of Hammurabi?", "answer": "Mesopotamia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339873", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", who is the companion of The Walrus?", "answer": "A Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acff", "question": "What building first appeared on the back of a $20 bill in 1928?", "answer": "The White House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61c", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Helium?", "answer": "He", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea34e2ff048f679a45aafd", "question": "Which is the densest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a360", "question": "What city dug the first subway?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071fa83745b36be73039ec", "question": "What does the abbreviation of Dana's police team, RCAT, stand for in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Revitalized Citizen Arbitration Team", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c53f0775fa611bce67c5", "question": "What part of a building do trusses support?", "answer": "Roof", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895b", "question": "What war is taking place in the novel \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5d", "question": "Clarence Darrow was coaxed out of retirement to defend what famous duo?", "answer": "Leopold & Loeb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2a", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Lagaan\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb4f47e83c707845b211d", "question": "What is the name of the chemical compound that makes peppers hot?", "answer": "Capsaicin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c86b877e98cb977789e4", "question": "Where can you see the petroglyphs of Newspaper Rock?", "answer": "Petrified Forrest National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b196", "question": "What is the birth name of US President Bill Clinton?", "answer": "William Jefferson Blythe III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fb", "question": "How many minutes does it take sunlight to reach Earth?", "answer": "8", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e6", "question": "Which state is closest to Bermuda?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a7f5876f5f79087132fb3e", "question": "Which religious figure is depicted in many of the tallest statues on Earth?", "answer": "Buddha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bcf3fb6c85e9e634ff63", "question": "Dakar is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59049b64cf93664eb104869f", "question": "Which producer on the TV show \"Lost\" co-created the comic book series \"Y: The Last Man\"?", "answer": "Brian K. Vaughan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe656ccae7e414034b5aed2", "question": "During the Roman Triumvirate of 42 BCE, what region of the Roman Republic was given to Lepidus?", "answer": "Hispania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a916", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort McHenry?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2b", "question": "What is James Dewar most famous for inventing?", "answer": "The vacuum flask", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2586331a458464a93c465", "question": "Which magazine received a backlash for publishing an April Fool's article entitled \"How to Beat Your Wife Without Leaving Marks\"?", "answer": "Playboy magazine (Romanian edition)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fda", "question": "What TV show did \"The Law and Harry McGraw\" spin off from?", "answer": "Murder, She Wrote", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3589c95db0d66a186cb54e", "question": "In which Brazilian city was F1 driver Ayrton Senna born?", "answer": "S\u00e3o Paulo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4b4c706d333868d34d6e2", "question": "Aristotle tutored which person who would go on to conquer most of the then-known world?", "answer": "Alexander the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f7", "question": "For how many years was the first generation Volkswagen Golf in production?", "answer": "9 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47f", "question": "Despite being fought by European countries, what modern-day country did the Battle of the Plains of Abraham take place?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76e", "question": "The Gaza Strip extends northeast from what peninsula?", "answer": "Sinai Peninsula", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523ecc736d4be723796b54", "question": "What three provinces requested a single Dominion be formed in 1867, thus beginning to shape modern Canada?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and the Province of Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008d9ccf842fa4c4ba96ab", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Oedipus marry?", "answer": "Jocasta, his mother", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393be", "question": "Who played the role of Cirus the Virus in the movie \"Con Air\"?", "answer": "John Malkovich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b9", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Cancer\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "Crab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cf2994b094db915830ad", "question": "The Bical grape originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8aa", "question": "In math, what lists can be summed into series?", "answer": "Sequences", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70b", "question": "How many calories must you burn to lose one pound?", "answer": "3500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02b", "question": "How old was Evel Knievel when he died?", "answer": "69", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0b", "question": "What author created the character of James Qwilleran?", "answer": "Lilian Jackson Braun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338888", "question": "What painter popularized soup cans and Brillo soap pad boxes?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb2", "question": "What US state has a Thames River?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff5172bff04d658268c92f9", "question": "What food did Ancient Egyptians use as a wound disinfectant?", "answer": "Moldy bread -- Egypt was onto something, because centuries later, penicillin would be derived from the Penicillium fungi.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a107", "question": "\"Eyes Wide Shut\" was the last film of which director?", "answer": "Stanley Kubrick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc93", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Buttonhook\"?", "answer": "Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049e53cf93664eb10486b3", "question": "The Koson District is a district in the Qashqadaryo Region of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5a", "question": "In a symphony orchestra, what instrument is played by the concertmaster?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26e", "question": "What is May's birthstone?", "answer": "Emerald", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8aa0201dd7bf43be5e755", "question": "What goes up and down but remains in the same place?", "answer": "Stairs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9b3908b8581f80b092c3", "question": "What three gaming consoles did Nintendo release in 2017?", "answer": "Nintendo Switch, New Nintendo 2DS XL, and Super NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc6", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by Elvis Costello?", "answer": "Radio Radio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52fb81bf59ab7d2e38117", "question": "Where is Bank of America headquartered?", "answer": "Charlotte, North Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b371201c3f17ccc40c8e1d", "question": "Considered to be the oldest pub in the US, what year was the White Horse Tavern of Rhode Island opened in?", "answer": "1673", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c390", "question": "What treat takes its name from a drink the Aztecs called Xocoatl?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3a46ff048f679a45ab2a", "question": "What is the name of the process where plants lose water in the atmosphere?", "answer": "Transpiration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b44", "question": "What name brand condiment is mentioned in the Jimmy Buffet song \"Cheeseburger in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Heinz 57", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66343a5bfecdd737e084e", "question": "Who first calculated Pi?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d93", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Dennis Coles?", "answer": "Ghostface Killah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e93", "question": "What movie did the villain Verbal Kint appear in?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae3", "question": "What is the capital of Cuba?", "answer": "Havana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b51", "question": "In Greek mythology, Jocasta is the mother of who?", "answer": "Oedipus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3f10b8b5801b8f54a7fbc", "question": "Visitors who kiss Ireland\u2019s Blarney Stone are said to be gifted with what?", "answer": "Eloquence", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65c911f3c0ead6880d616", "question": "What natural occurrence was said to have helped the British navy defeat the Spanish Armada in 1588?", "answer": "A Protestant Wind", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d57", "question": "Whose mysterious murder ends the film \"Gorillas in the Mist\"?", "answer": "Dian Fossey's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba204874c93a3298b212e", "question": "Innsbruck is the capital of which Austrian state?", "answer": "Tyrol", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010cabb0775fa611bce67fe", "question": "Emetophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Vomit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1d", "question": "The March of Dimes was originally founded to help find a vaccine for what?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ac", "question": "Which country were the 1952 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062a58c9d816e292245c17", "question": "What is Judy Chicago's most well-known work?", "answer": "Regarded as the first epic feminist artwork, \"The Dinner Party\" functions as a symbolic history of women in Western civilization.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf3", "question": "What two things are being compared in a stock's \"P/E ratio\"?", "answer": "Share price and earnings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49e", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f44", "question": "\"Pee-Wee's Big Adventure\" is to recover what beloved stolen item?", "answer": "His bike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2f1d58d116dab4aecb46", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c5", "question": "What is the official state animal of the US state of Oregon?", "answer": "The beaver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1c", "question": "In what 1992 movie does Jennifer Jason Leigh play a dangerous \"roommate from Hell\"?", "answer": "Single White Female", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be90", "question": "What soft drink line was named after a competitor's unusually tall bottles?", "answer": "Nehi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a69d", "question": "The Shenandoah Valley is located in which eastern US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ec", "question": "Which TV production company brought the show \"Late Night With David Letterman\" to NBC?", "answer": "Worldwide Pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa40", "question": "What country's explorers discovered the site of Pensacola, Florida?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a63d", "question": "What US city is home to the Field Museum of Natural History?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918d", "question": "Which is the only one of the Seven Dwarfs without a beard?", "answer": "Dopey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a889", "question": "What two US state capitals are named for people who were executed?", "answer": "Raleigh and St. Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f8", "question": "Which is the shallowest sea on Earth?", "answer": "Sea of Azov", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391dc", "question": "Who played Mr. White in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Harvey Keitel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f705ba9e54d890926f6d5", "question": "What is the only South American country to use the U.S. dollar as its official currency?", "answer": "Ecuador -- After a financial crisis in 2000, Ecuador switched from its currency to U.S. dollars due to citizen demand for dollars.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc6", "question": "What popular soft drink claims to contain 23 flavors?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd08", "question": "What of the so-called original six teams was the NHL's first US franchise?", "answer": "The Boston Bruins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c60", "question": "What liqueur was Vincent Van Gogh said to be heavily drinking heavily the night he cut off his ear?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a95", "question": "What late 1980s ABC TV show was the first entertainment program to film an episode in Moscow?", "answer": "Head of the Class", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59decf64ea2747c8aff16d1e", "question": "Junko Tabei was famous for being the first woman to do what?", "answer": "Reach the summit of Mount Everest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523e9f736d4be723796b52", "question": "What is Toronto\u2019s Pearson International Airport code?", "answer": "YYZ", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a996", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Lassen Peak\"?", "answer": "The United States", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe909eb01dd7bf43be5e893", "question": "What is trepanning?", "answer": "The drilling of holes in the head and scraping or cutting of the skull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa20", "question": "What is the capital of Comoros?", "answer": "Moroni", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ca", "question": "Who authored the famous poem \"The Charge of the Light Brigade\"?", "answer": "Alfred, Lord Tennyson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a1a3de12f2a7826b9b872a", "question": "Forty six represents the atonomic number of which element?", "answer": "Palladium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f25", "question": "What comedy hit was produced under the working title \"East Great Falls High\"?", "answer": "American Pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5d", "question": "In the series Harry Potter, what is the spell for water-making?", "answer": "Aguamenti", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2b", "question": "Who is Jamie Lee Curtis' mother?", "answer": "Janet Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51c1aff04d658268c9314", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31c", "question": "Which character did John Ritter play on the TV show \"Three's Company\"?", "answer": "Jack Tripper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd5de60499cffc60b84232", "question": "Which country is ruled by the Al Sabah dynasty?", "answer": "Kuwait", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f25", "question": "In the King James Bible, all but three books of the New Testament end with what word?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc8e76de0eb824d405300", "question": "Which borough has New York City's only surf beach?", "answer": "Queens -- Rockaway Beach, just a subway ride away from Manhattan, is the only surf-able beach in NYC limits.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f55", "question": "What James Joyce story collection begins with \"The Sisters\" and ends with \"The Dead\"?", "answer": "Dubliners", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049903cf93664eb104868d", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Tennessee?", "answer": "Nashville", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008e011f4f3bc4a292f862e", "question": "In old world Europe, which holiday used to be celebrated on April 1?", "answer": "New Year's Day -- Pope Gregory XIII ordered the implementation of the Gregorian Calendar in 1582, which changed it to January 1.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c8", "question": "Whose first film was the documentary \"Roger & Me\"?", "answer": "Michael Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa15", "question": "What line on a map connects places of equal rainfall?", "answer": "Isohyet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fa", "question": "With which group would you associate the songs \"Light My Fire\" and \"Hello I Love You\"?", "answer": "The Doors", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73377eec85e375820b221", "question": "What was the name of the antisemitic laws passed in Nazi Germany on September 15, 1935?", "answer": "Nuremberg Law", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c5d49076251badbead2", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "The term \"motel\" originated with the\u00a0Milestone Mo-Tel, which was constructed in 1925 by Arthur Heineman.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca9", "question": "Al Pacino's satanic character in \"The Devil's Advocate\" is named for what author?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "entertainment"}]